Slow Loris Press Records
© 2002 University of Connecticut
Slow Loris Press Records.
1971-1984.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Slow Loris Press.
5 linear feet.
The Slow Loris Press was a independent non-profit venture headed by Anthony and Patricia Petrosky. The Slow Loris Press focused on publishing a poetry magazine called Rapport which evolved into a more wide ranging format with the start of the Slow Loris Reader (SLR) in 1978. The Press also published chapbooks and broadsides. It ceased operation in 1984 principally due to insufficient financial support.
MSS19980212
History
The Slow Loris Press was an independent non-profit venture headed by Anthony and Patricia Petrosky. The Slow Loris Press focused on publishing a poetry magazine called the Rapport that evolved into a wider format with the start of the Slow Loris Reader (SLR) in 1978. The press also published poetry anthologies of various authors, as well as, the Rapport and SLR which drew upon numerous poets' work. The Slow Loris Press originated in Buffalo, New York, where Anthony Petrosky (also called Tony) taught at the Free School of Buffalo. When Anthony received a position at the University of Pittsburgh in 1975 the couple and magazine headed there. In February of 1978 the couple had a child named Matthew. By 1978 and the launching of the SLR, Patricia (also called Patty) Petrosky controlled most of the press's operations, including the editorship.
Financial support for the press came from magazine subscriptions, sales of its book and from available government grants. In the 1980s the press encountered trouble competing for National Endowment for the Humanities grants as well as more local funding options. In 1986, with two books by Martha Friedberg and Janet Sternberg in production, the press halted operations amid financial and personal troubles. Influenced by these setbacks the Slow Loris Press ceased operation in 1986.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes manuscript submissions, correspondence with authors, business records, galleys, artworks and broadsides. Numerous drafts and copies of issues for both Rapport and the Slow Loris Reader issues are contained in the collection. The Rapport, published between 1974 and 1978, focused on young unpublished poets. The later SLR widened its scope to include literary reviews, fiction, and the work of established authors and poets. This collection does not include all issues of the Rapport or SLR. Readers will discover that the documents for Rapport 9 and SLR 1+2 offer a complete look at the drafting and editing process. Similarly, there are gaps in the coverage of chapbooks, but the drafts and revisions of "God's Helicopter" offer a complete look at how the press crafted its publications. Readers will wish to consulate the several books that are a part of this collection, as well as, check the catalog to find other Slow Loris publications in the Dodd Center's holdings.
A sizeable series of correspondence and letters from frequent contributors follows. The majority of these contributors were fellow members of academia; instructors, professors, or Ph.D candidates. There is indication that both the audience and the contribution to the magazine were not geographically restricted, but also never attained any mass following. Most of the printing runs were below one thousand. Unfortunately no records exist within this collection to ascertain the exact number of readers and fans. Some of the more noteworthy contributors are: Robert Bly, Richard Hugo, Philip Levine, David Ignatow and William Stafford.
Organization
Arrangement of collection maintains the basic divisions of the creator. The correspondence series has been arranged alphabetically. The publication series has been arranged by the date of publication with the series being arranged to highlight the most significant documents.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections have a substantial collection of materials pertaining to literary presses, literature and children's literature. Also several chapbooks and other Slow Loris Press publications are a part of the Dodd Center's literary collection; check the catalog for details. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
SEPARATED MATERIAL
BOOKS: The Animal in the Bush by David Ignatow; The End of the Ice Age by Ed Ochester; I Would Like to Also Mention Aluminum by William Stafford; Road Ends at Tahola by Richard Hugo; Slow Loris Reader IV; BROADSIDES: Abortion by William Heyen; Abstract Love Poem by John Logan; Anthropological by Marvin Bell; Camping alone in Winter by Anthony Piccione; Cicadas by Cid Corman; Departures by Jerome Mazzaro; The Estate by Mac Hammond; For Lori by David Ignatow; Heroes by Carl Dennis; Lesson by Guillevic translated by Ted Savory; Letter by Robert Hass; Letter Home by Shreela Ray; Matthew's Compleat Palmistry by William Matthews; Maybe there is by William Stafford; The Mower by William Heyen; Night Begins by Tony Petrosky; Poem for John Logan by Tony Petrosky; Rocks are not sad by Morton Marcus; Several Ways of Beating around the Bush by William Jurgels; Slow Loris Press Broadsides Series III- Eleven broadsides; Slow Loris Press Broadsides Series IV- Thirteen broadsides; The Snail's Road by James Wright; Sparrow by Philip Dow; Tondelayo by Louis Simpson; The Tower at the End of the World by Ed Ochester; Wedneday's Boy by Tony Petrosky.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Hugo, Richard, 1923-1982 --Correspondence.; Levine, Philip, 1928- --Correspondence.; Stafford, William, 1914- --Correspondence.; Wakoski, Diane--Correspondence.; Rapport (Pittsburgh); Slow Loris reader; American literature--Periodicals.; Periodicals, Publishing of.; Authors and publishers--United States.; Publishers and publishing--United States.; American literature--20th century.; American poetry--20th century.; Little presses--New York (State); Little presses--Pennsylvania.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.; Typescripts.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Books.; Posters.; Contracts.; Poems.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Organizational and Operations Materials,1971-1984
  - Fiscal, Grants and Organizational Materials,1971-1984 (Box 1:1)
  - Pestroskys' Personal Info,1971-1984 (Box 1:2)
  - Subscriptions,undated (Box 1:3)
  - Public Relations, Book Awards,1971-1984 (Box 1:4)
- Series II: Slow Loris Press Publications,1971-1986
  - RAPPORT MAGAZINE,1972-1977
  - Rapport 2+3,1972 (Box 2:5)
  - Rapport 9,1976 (Box 2:6)
  - Rapport 9: Drafts,1976 (Box 2:7)
  - Rapport 9: Poetry,1976 (Box 2:8)
  - Rapport 9: Layout,1976 (Box 2:9)
  - Rapport 10: Poetry and Drafts,1977 (Box 2:10)
  - Rapport 10: Correspondence,1977 (Box 2:11)
  - THE SLOW LORIS READER,1978-1980
  - Slow Loris Reader: 1+2 Poems Folder 1,1978 (Box 2:12)
  - SLR 1+2: Poems Folder 2,1978 (Box 2:13)
  - SLR: 1+2 Letters,1978 (Box 2:14)
  - SLR 3,1979 (Box 2:15)
  - SLR 4,1980 (Box 2:16)
  - SLR 4 :Drafts,1980 (Box 2:17)
  - CHAPBOOKS,1974-1986
  - Book Flyers,undated (Box 3:18)
  - Machines: William Heyen,undated (Box 3:19)
  - I Would Like to Also Mention Aluminum: William Stafford,1976 (Box 3:20)
  - The End of the Ice Age: Ed Ochester,1977 (Box 3:21)
  - Waking Up Late: Gary Eddy,1977 (Box 3:22)
  - Tuning: Jane Bailey,1978 (Box 3:23)
  - Songs of Autumn: Sigitas Geda trans. Jonas Zdanys,1978 (Box 3:24)
  - Green in the Body: Robert Winner,1978 (Box 3:25)
  - Polar Sun: Sandi Piccione,undated (Box 3:26)
  - Oblique Light: Lynn Emmanuel,undated (Box 3:27)
  - Oblique Light: Proofs,undated (Box 3:28)
  - Interstate: Marie Harris,1980 (Box 4:29)
  - Heart, Grain: Nels Nelson,1980 (Box 4:30)
  - The Ancient Wars: Paul Zimmer,1980 (Box 4:31)
  - God's Helicopter: Lee Gutkind,1983 (Box 4:32)
  - God's Helicopter: Drafts,1983 (Box 4:33)
  - God's Helicopter: Galleys Folder 11983 (Box 4:34)
  - God's Helicopter: Galleys Folder 2,1983 (Box 4:35)
  - God's Helicopter: Book Mockup Text Only Version,1983 (Box 4:36)
  - God's Helicopter: Book Mockup Illustrations Added Version,1983 (Box 5:37)
  - God's Helicopter: Draft,1983 (Box 5:38)
  - Girl's Latin: Janet Sternberg,1986 (Box 5:39)
  - BROADSIDES,1971-1984
  - Poems for Broadsides,1971-1984 (Box 5:40)
- Series III: Correspondence,1971-1984
  - Bailey, Jane,1974-1978 (Box 6:41)
  - Bly, Robert,1970-1979 (Box 6:42)
  - Buckley, Chris,1978-1979 (Box 6:43)
  - Casey, Michael,undated (Box 6:44)
  - Chuddihy, Michael,1973-1975 (Box 6:45)
  - Eddy, Gary,undated (Box 6:46)
  - Emmanuel, Lynn,undated (Box 6:47)
  - Friedberg, Martha,undated (Box 6:48)
  - Harris, Marie,undated (Box 6:49)
  - Hugo, Richard,1975-1977 (Box 6:50)
  - Ignatow, David,1971-1983 (Box 6:51)
  - Ignatow, Rose Graubart: Folder 1,1971-1983 (Box 6:52)
  - Ignatow, Rose Graubart: Folder 2,1971-1983 (Box 6:53)
  - Igantow, Rose Graubart: Artwork,undated (Box 6:54)
  - Kicknosway, Faye,1974 (Box 6:55)
  - Levine, Philip,1982-1985 (Box 6:56)
  - Logan, John,1974-1982 (Box 6:57)
  - Marcus, Morton,1975 (Box 6:58)
  - Perret, Nell,1973-1974 (Box 7:59)
  - Piccione, Sandi,1978-1979 (Box 7:60)
  - Soto, Gary,1979-1980 (Box 7:61)
  - Stafford, William,1972-1980 (Box 7:62)
  - Wakoski, Diane,1971-1980 (Box 7:63)
  - Water, Michael,1973-1979 (Box 7:64)
  - Winner, Robert,1978-1982 (Box 7:65)
  - Zdanys, Jonas,undated (Box 7:66)
  - Zimmer, Paul,undated (Box 7:67)
  - A-E (various authors),undated (Box 7:68)
  - F-K (various authors),undated (Box 7:69)
  - L-M (various authors),undated (Box 7:70)
  - N-P (various authors),undated (Box 7:71)
  - O-S (various authors),undated (Box 7:72)
  - T-Z,(various authors)undated (Box 7:73)
- Series IV: Printing Materials; Artwork and Negatives,1976
  - I Would Also Like to Mention Aluminum Printing Negatives,1976 (Box 8:74)
  - Cover of Rapport 10,1977 (Box 8:75)
  - Cover of Rapport 11/Slow Loris Reader,1978 (Box 8:76)
  - The Ride: Artwork for City Lights unknown (Box 8:77)
  - Escape with Performing Hen: Artwork for City Lights unknown (Box 8:78)
  - King of Spades: Artwork for City Lights unknown (Box 8:79)
  - Daybreak Meets Crazy Psychoanalyst: Artwork for City Lights unknown (Box 8:80)